Due to the current emergency situation, all phone lines have been suspended.
No good, huh? Even the phones are out.
The buses and trains have all stopped too.
Guess I won't be making it. Too bad...
I should head to a shelter.
Focus all fire on the target!
Sorry to have kept you waiting!
The target is still intact. It is progressing toward tokyo-3!
The Air Force is unable to damage it!
Throw everything at it! Mobilize the 4th armored division to intercept!
Don't hold back! Destroy the target at all cost!
How?! That was a direct hit!
The tank battalion was completely destroyed. Missiles had no effect on it...
Damnit! What are we supposed to do against something like that?!
As we thought, an A.T. field...
Yes, conventional weapons are useless against the Angel.
Understood. We will proceed as planned.
No way... They're using an N2 Mine?!
Get down!
We did it!
I'm afraid we've left nothing for you to do.
Shockwave incoming!
Are you okay?
Yeah. I just have some dirt in my mouth.
That's alright.
Are you ready? And--push!
Thanks a lot. Good job.
Ah, I should be thanking you Katsuragi-san.
Call me Misato.
It's nice to meet you, Ikari Shinji-kun.
Me too.
What is the target's status?
There's no way it could survive such a massive explosion.
Recovering image.
Our trump card failed!
How is this possible...
It's a monster!
The gate will be closing. Please be careful.
Secret Military Agency NERV?
Yes, it is a private organization under the direct supervision of the United Nations.
It's where my father is right?
Yes, well. Do you know what he does?
"Work of utmost importance in the protection of humanity," is what the teacher said.
From this point on, you will be in command of this operation. Show us what you can do.
Understood.
Ikari-kun, from our available weapons, we admit we have no effective means of disabling the target.
Are you confident you can succeed?
It is why NERV exists.
Are we heading to where my father is?
Well, yes. We are.
Father...
Oh, were you given an I.D. by your father?
Ah, here it is.
Thanks.
Go ahead and read this.
NERV.
My father's work.
Is there something I'm needed for?
Of course. He wouldn't send me a letter for nothing.
You think your father is a tough guy? Me too.
Huh?
Amazing! It's a real Geofront!
Yes. This is our secret base: NERV Headquarters.
It is the foundation for rebuilding our world and the last defence for humanity.
Ah... Ritsuko!
You're 12 minutes over schedule. It doesn't take this long to pick someone up.
We're short on manpower and we don't have any time to waste, Captain Katsuragi.
Sorry.
This is the man's son?
Yes.
I am director of the 1st science division of E-project, Akagi Ritsuko.
It's nice to meet you.
Me too.
Well then, I'll leave the rest to you.
Meeting his son after 3 years...
Ikari Shinij-kun, there's something I want to show you.
This is the ultimate humanoid fighting machine. The cyborg Evangelion.
That is Unit 01.
It is our last and greatest weapon.
This is my fathers work?
Yes it is.
It's been a long time.
Father...
Prepare to sortie.
Sortie?!
But Unit 00 is still frozen!
Unless... You intend to use Unit 01?
There is no other choice.
Ikari Shinji-kun.
Y--Yes?
You will pilot it.
Father, why did you call me here?
You know why.
So, you want me to step into this and fight that thing outside?
Exactly.
No, I won't! Not after all this time!
For so long I've thought you didn't care about me!
I called you because I need you.
Why me?
Because no one else can.
I can't do it...
I've never seen or heard of this thing. It's impossible!
You'll learn to.
No... I can't do it!
I can't pilot this!
If you're going to pilot it, do it now. Otherwise get out!
The bastard has found his way here.
Shinji-kun, there isn't much time.
Pilot it!
No...
After coming all this way, this is ridiculous!
Shinji-kun, why did you come here?
Don't run away. From your father, and above all, from yourself!
I know! But, I can't do it!
Fuyutsuki.
Wake up Rei.
Can we use her?
She's not dead.
Understood.
Rei.
Yes.
The spare is useless. You'll have to go one more time.
Restart Unit 01's core unit to L-00 Type.
Roger, discontinuing current process. Begining reformat.
I'm useless again... As expected...
Are you okay?!
I can't run away, I can't run away, I can't run away, I can't run away...
I can't run away!
I'll do it. I'll pilot it.
Freezing process has been halted.
Flywheel rotation has stopped. Connections have been released.
No problems with auxillary voltage.
Stoplight plug draining complete.
Roger, inserting Entry Plug.
Spinal conduction system opened, connection established.
Probe needle driving in.
Prime synch established. Analyzing nerve connections.
Reading of -0.051% within limitations.
-The plug has been fixed.
-Roger, starting first contact.
Flooding Entry Plug.
Hey, what is th--
It's alright.
Once the LCL fills your lungs, it will provide oxygen directly to your blood.
You'll get used to it.
Master power source connection complete.
Roger.
Starting second contact.
Establishing interface.
No problems detected in A10 nervous system.
LCL levels nominal.
Japanese has been fixed as the primary mode of operation.
No problems detected with initial contacts.
Communication lines open.
Risk 1405 all clear. Synapse reading: Synchro rate 41.3%
Plug suit auxilary support functioning perfectly... Amazing.
Harmonics are in normal levels. Everything's under control.
This will work!
Prepare to launch!
Release 1st lock bolt!
1st lock released.
Transfering umbilical bridge.
Release 2nd lock bolt!
Removing the first restraint.
Removing the second restraint.
Cancel safety devices 1 through 15.
Safety devices canceled. Unit 01 is free.
Internal power supply charge complete.
No problems detected with external power supply.
Understood. Evangelion Unit 01 transfering to launch pad.
BALLSBALLSBALLS
The course is clear. All green!
Launch preparations complete.
Understood.
Are you sure?
Of course.
We must defeat the Angels, or we will all die here.
Ikari, are you really okay with this?
Launch!
Are you ready, Shinji-kun?
Y--yeah.
Release the final safety lock!
Evangelion Unit 01, lift off!
Shinji-kun, focus only on walking now.
Walk...
It walked!
Shinji-kun, get up!
Hurry, get up right now!
Shinji-kun, calm down!
That isn't your arm!
How is the Evangelion's defense system?
I can't get a signal.
The field isn't developing.
No good?!
The left arm has been fractured!
The circuits have snapped!
Shinji-kun, dodge it!
The frontal cranium has been cracked!
The armor can't withstand much more!
Skull fracture! Damage unknown!
Activity halted!
What is the status?
Synchro graph inverting, pulse-flow is reversing!
Cut the circuits!
It's no good--The signal is being rejected! It's not connecting!
What about Shinji-kun?!
No response from the monitoring system. Life signs unknown!
Unit 01 is completely silent.
Misato!
It's come to this...
Halt military operations! The pilot's life is our main priority!
Eject the plug by force!
It's no good! It's not responding!
What is this?!
Eva is restarting!
Impossible... how is it moving?
It can't be...
It's gone berserk...
Looks like we've won.
A.T. field?!
It's no good, the A.T. field is at it's limit!
Eva can't even touch the Angel!
Left arm restored!
Incredible...
Unit 01 is expanding it's own A.T. field! It's neutralizing phase space!
No, it's eroding the Angel's own A.T. field.
To destroy it's A.T. field so easily...
What is Eva's status?
That is Eva's...
True form...
Have you decided on a name?
If it's a boy, Shinji. If it's a girl, then Rei.
Shinji... Rei...
Shinji... Shinji... Ayanami...
Shinji... Rei... Rei...
Ikari... Rei...
No... Ayanami...
Rei!
An unknown ceiling.
If the fourth Angel attacked us now, we would be annihilated.
Not to mention it was the Third Child who was there for Unit 01's first start-up.
Just more of the same, am I right?
Repairing Unit 01 is a huge unexpected cost.
Compared to a frozen Unit 00, that is hardly a problem.
Eva Unit 01's recovery operation is complete.
It is currently locked in cage 6.
A 10 day examination is planned.
-Is there an internal record from it's berzerker period?
-It was functioning at zero capacity. Nothing was written.
We'll get the results in cryptogenics I suppose.
Eva's certainly an effective weapon...
A little overkill, don't you think?
Inconveniences aside, Unit 01 should have performed at least until the fifth Angel.
Don't worry. Unit 01 is not our only weapon.
Unit 02's pilot is currently being evaluated in Germany.
The construction of Unit 03 is also progressing as planned.
Overseeing NERV and Eva with discretion is your primary duty.
We will not stand for any repeated disappointments.
That's right. To exterminate the Angels is but one step in fulfilling our contract with Lilith.
To execute the Human Instrumentality Project is our final wish.
I understand. Everything will go according to Seele's scenario.
The complete collapse of the Angel's A.T. field was far beyond our expectations.
The blood is like a lake from hell... It reminds me of the Second Impact.
It makes me sick.
For Eva to defeat the Angels is the only hope left for humanity.
It's the pilot who carries the burden of that hope.
Alone?
Yes, his room is in Block 6. I assume that isn't a problem.
That's fine.
Is that really okay, Shinji-kun?
It's okay, I prefer being alone.
It's always the same wherever I am.
What did you say?!
Like I was saying, Shinji-kun would be much better off at my place.
Besides, I have authorization from above.
Don't worry, it's not like I'll have my hands all over him.
That goes without saying! If that's supposed to be...
I was just kidding, jeez...
Alright, looks like we're having a party tonight!
What for?
A welcoming party of course! You're a new member of the family.
Ah, so you're going to move?
Yes, I never thought this city would become a battlefield.
Really! My husband said we should evacuate soon.
Just today, over 100 people left the city.
No matter how powerful a fortress this city is, those NERV people still don't know what they're doing.
Just thinking about yesterday makes me shudder...
I know...
Oh yeah, we'll be making a quick stop on the way.
Where to?
A really cool place.
The city is deserted.
It's time.
Amazing... The buildings are rising up!
This is our stronghold against the onslaught of the Angels: Tokyo-3.
This is our city.
This is the city you protected.
I think your things have already been delivered.
To be honest, I've only moved here recently.
Alright, come on in.
Sorry for disturbing you. (Ojamashimasu)
Shinji-kun, this is your home now.
I--I'm home. (Tadaima)
Welcome home. (Okaerinasai)
Ah, it's a little messy in here. Don't you mind that.
A little...
Messy?
Oh sorry, there should be some food in the refrigerator.
O--Okay!
Ice...
Junk food...
Endless beer...
What kind of life does she lead?
-Itadakimasu!
-Itadakimasu.
Ah! I live for this!
Not hungry? For instant food, it's pretty good.
Ah, well... I'm just not used to this sort of meal.
No way! You can't be so picky!
Uhhh, no, that's not it... Ummm...
Pretty fun, huh?
Having a meal with another person?
Y--yeah.
Alright! Since this is your home now, you have to act like it!
Okay.
Come on... "Yes, yes, yes, yes." Don't be so boring!
You're a boy aren't you?! Pull yourself together!
Okay.
Well, whatever. Go take a bath and wash away all that negativity.
Bathing is laundry of life!
Misato-san!
What?
Ah, him? He's a hot-weather penguin. Sort of a friend of mine.
That penguin lives here?!
I've had him for 15 years. His name is Pen-pen.
He's another member of the family.
Anyway... Shouldn't you be hiding that?
A little obvious, don't you think? Maybe I'm the one who'll be seen through...
Katsuragi Misato-san...
She's not a bad person.
Bathing is the laundry of life!
In here, more bad memories come up than others.
How is Rei's current state?
Noon... Did you go to the hospital?
There are no problems. We will prepare to re-start the frozen Unit 00.
How is your son? His mental state must be very unstable.
He's been released. Still, his condition is a good excuse to cancel the freezing on Unit 00.
Yes... It was Captain Katsuragi's proposal after all.
Even without a preliminary report, they suddenly elected three boys.
All of this corresponding with the Angel's attack.
In addition, forcibly confiscating Commander Ikari's son.
Certainly there must be some resentment.
Even knowing the Angel has been defeated, I feel suprisingly...
Unhappy.
Another unknown ceiling...
It feels natural.
Because I don't know anything of this city.
This is your home now.
Why am I here?
Shinji-kun? I'm coming in.
I forgot to tell you something.
You did a good thing.
You should be proud.
Good-night, Shinji-kun.
Cheer up.
Sorry, exchange student. I have to hit you.
I just won't be satisfied if I don't.
Real sorry. That guy's little sister was injured in that big incident the other day.
Or, something like that.
It's not like I piloted it because I wanted to.
Where are the people who praise me, I wonder...
If it was such a good thing to pilot Eva, why am I getting hit?
Are you ready, Shinji-kun?
Yes.
Within the Angel is a central core.
Destroying the core is the only way to destroy the Angel's physical form.
Therefore, always aim for the center, and squeeze the switch.
We will work on accuracy. You will remember the sensation when the time comes.
Yes.
Good. We will continue practice with this Induction Mode.
Shinji-kun sure has brought himself around to piloting Eva, hasn't he?
He does whatever people tell him to.
It's how he goes through life.
Aim at center target, switch... Aim at center target, switch...
Which reminds me...
Shinji-kun was hit by a student at his new school.
Is his security detail working alright?
There's no problem with the secret agency's surveillance.
Besides, it wasn't very bad.
It was better for there to be no outside interference.
Doesn't he live with you?
His care is your responsibility too, you know.
It's for that reason.
It's difficult... He's just too naive.
Is that a complaint?
You were the one who was so adamant about taking him in.
Shut up...
Well, he doesn't have much of a personality for making friends.
Have you heard of the "Hedgehog's dilema?"
Hedgehog? The little prickly things?
If a hedgehog wants to be close with other hedgehogs...
The closer they become, the more they hurt eachother.
People are the same way.
The same is true of Shinji-kun.
The more pain his heart endures, the more afraid he becomes.
Well, eventually he'll realize.
Growing up means being hurt whether you're close with others...
or if they're kept at a distance.
I suppose you're right.
Still, when will we get the B-Section equipment repair estimate?
Eva's maintenance and battle capacity is their main priority.
Money isn't a problem.
My butt is freezing...
An emergency call...
I'll go on ahead.
The object has been visually identified.
E747 has also confirmed the object.
Analysis indicates Pattern Blue. There's no doubt--it's the fifth Angel.
All hands to Stage One Battle Stations.
Roger. Preparing anti-aircraft measures.
Tokyo-3 transforming to battle formation.
Initiating Central Block.
Districts 1 through 7 of Central Block transfered.
Notification to all government ministries completed.
Target is steadily progressing.
All anti-aircraft systems currently functioning at 48%.
What is the status of civilians and noncombatants?
Reports confirm they've already been evacuated to shelters.
All junior and primary students, please stay with your designated...
At it again?
There's only letters on the screen again.
It's an information blackout. They won't show us regular citizens anything.
Even if this is a big event.
They're just wasting tax money...
In this world, people don't care how many bullets are fired.
The Japanese government is demanding we send out an Evangelion.
How annoying. They don't have to tell us.
Starting Entry Plug. LCL levels nominal...
Father isn't even here. Why am I piloting this again?
Even getting hit over it.
Hey, I wanna talk to you about something.
-What about?
-Come here.
Alright...
Yeah, yeah! That's what I thought.
-Class Rep!
-What?
We both have to go to the bathroom, apparently.
Come on, you had your chance earlier!
So, what's this about?
Before I die, I'm going to see at least one of them.
That battle up there?
It's the real thing! Who knows when the next enemy will come here...
Kensuke, you're nuts.
If I miss this chance, I might never get another!
Come on... Just help me open the gate.
Guess I've got no choice. You sure don't give in, do you?
Shinji-kun, are you ready to sortie?
...Yes.
Good. To neutralize the enemy's A.T. field will require rapid, simultaneous fire.
Just like in practice. You'll be fine.
...Yes.
Launch!
Incredible! This was worth the trouble!
Just in time!
It's here.
-Aim at center target, switch...
-A.T. field is developing.
-Just as planned. Are you ready, Shinji-kun?
-Yes.
Yes.
Idiot! The smoke is conceling the enemy!
Looks like it got him.
He'll be alright.
We're sending up a reserve rifle!
Take it!
Shinji-kun...? Shinji-kun?!
Oh man... That hit really knocked him out.
Sh--Shut up!
Umbillical Cable has been disconnected!
Eva switching to internal power!
Active time remaining is 4 minutes 53 seconds!
It's coming this way!
Shinji-kun, are you alright?! Shinji-kun!
-Can he hear me?
-No problems detected. It should run!
Shinji-kun's classmates?!
What are they doing there?!
Why won't he fight it?!
Because we're here... He can't move!
Unit 01 will reach active time limit in 3 minutes 28 seconds!
Contact with outer surface, damage at 58%!
Shinji-kun, let those two into the cockpit!
Once they're in, get out of there! We'll regroup later!
You two, get in!
What? There's water!
-The camera!
-Entry Plug restarting.
Penetrating through third protection film!
Now! Retreat!
Take recovery route 34. Head to the mountain's eastern side!
Hey exchange student, she said, "Run away!"
Exchange student!
I can't run away... I can't run away...
Progressive Knife equipped!
Shinji-kun, listen to me! Fall back now!
Shinji-kun!
That idiot!
Unit 01 will reach active time limit in 30 seconds.
28, 27, 26...
25, 24, 23, 22...
13, 12, 11, 10, 9...
8, 7, 6, 5, 4...
3, 2, 1...
Eva Unit 01 has ceased all activity.
The target has completely collapsed.
Why did you ignore my orders?
I'm sorry.
I'm the one responsible for this military operation, correct?
Yes.
When I give you an order, it is your duty to follow them.
Do you understand me?
Yes.
Make this the last time.
Do you really understand what I'm telling you?
Yes, I understand Misato-san.
It's fine, we won didn't we?
If you tell me to pilot Eva, I will.
That's enough. Go back and get some rest.
He has no intention of coming back.
That idiot.
Ikari, Ikari Shinji.
Absent so soon after transfering...
Well regardless, let's continue yesterday's test.
That's enough...
Just go back to Misato-san!
Did walking around for days cheer you up, Ikari Shinji-kun?
Not really. It doesn't matter what I do.
I'm not free to do anything.
Anyway, I have to pilot Eva, don't I?
It's the only reason my father called me here.
Fine. I'll pilot it.
If that's what everyone wants, that's what I'll do.
What everyone wants...? What do you want?
It doesn't matter what I want... Everyone knows it.
Father, Misato-san, even an injured Ayanami...
Cut it out!
This has nothing to do with anyone else!
You decide whether you continue to pilot Eva!
If you want to leave this terrible place, fine!
Everyone has free will. Do as you please!
Eventually your son will act as planned.
Yes. Next we will have Rei move in closer to him.
The plan has not changed.
A 14 year old scenario...
Our fate rests on children.
Isn't it a bit cruel?
Let's stop right there--Go ahead and hit me!
I won't feel satisfied if you don't.
Well, seeing as he's so sincere, I'd go for it.
Now we're even. I'm sorry for hitting you, Ikari.
Go for it, Tayoko!
Hey, they're looking over here!
Suzuhara has a weird look in his eyes.
Ikari-kun!
Ayanami Rei, age 14.
She was the first candidate chosen by the Marduk Report.
The First Child.
Specifically, she is the exclusive pilot of the experimental Evangelion Unit 00.
Her personal history is non-existant. Everything has been erased.
Why did my father rescue her?
Start-up system corrupted!
-Problem detected in Stage 3.
-Nervous system elements rejected.
Pulse-flow is reversing! Unable to stop it!
Direct monitoring disrupted.
Entry Plug in unstable depths, Eva is refusing to release it!
Halt all contacts. Break circuits 1 through 6.
It's no good, the signal isn't connecting!
Eva Unit 00 is out of control!
Stop the experiment. Cut all power.
Yes sir!
Unit 00 is currently on reserve power.
Complete shut-down in 35 seconds!
Suspension in process.
It's dangerous! Step back!
Auto-ejection system engaging!
Damn it!
Quickly, release the bakelite!
Rei!
Complete shut-down in 10 seconds!
8, 7, 6, 5...
4, 3, 2, 1.
Unit 00 has ceased all activity.
Rei! Are you okay?!
Rei!
Good.
It's rather unbelievable isn't it?
Despite the official report having been eliminated, it's not so hard to understand.
After The berzerker incident, Unit 00 is suddenly unfrozen.
Isn't that a bit hasty?
Another Angel suddenly appeared. Our combat readiness is an urgent priority.
I suppose that's true...
Rei's re-start test has already been authorized.
Using Unit 00 won't be a problem.
If we repair a few nerve connections...
Immediate re-deployment, right?
Ayanami...
Why is she always alone?
Understood. Synchro Test, Program 508 complete.
Shinji-kun, good job today.
Well, how is living together with him?
So-so. It'll take some getting used to.
Is there any leftover tension?
It's your first time living with a man, isn't it?
This isn't like 8 years ago.
"Love" isn't involved this time...
I wonder... Shinji-kun did stay because of you.
You're wrong.
I think... he stayed because of his father.
He only wants just one word of praise.
He's so lonely... he only needs a little affection.
He's a very distant man... like your father.
Why does he pay so little attention to him...
And he seems to speak only to Rei.
It's a terrible balance.
Men nowadays don't seem very interested in me either.
It's not a very good time for women.
Well, then... It's time we get back.
A worker bee as usual.
Misato. Here is Shinji-kun's official security card...
...and Ayanami Rei's renewed card. They were delivered some time ago.
Tomorrow, give them both to Shinji-kun, would you?
I guess so.
Ayanami Rei...
Why was my father laughing?
Why doesn't he laugh with me?
Excuse me...
Excuse me, it's Ikari!
Ayanami, I'm coming in!
Ayanami's?
Ummm...
I wasn't trying to...
Could you move?
What is it?
Ummm, I...
I was supposed to...
The uhhh...
The card! The card was renewed and... that's why I...
That's why I... I wasn't trying to...
Ritsuko-san gave it to me because she forgot... It's the truth.
No one answered when I rang, and I had a key...
Central Dogma is currently open.
Group 3 through Communication Gate 4 please.
Here's your new card. Ritsuko-san left it with me.
I'm sorry for what I did.
What about?
Aren't you afraid, Ayanami?
Getting into that Evangelion again...
Why?
I heard you got hurt in that test... Are you going to be okay?
Yes. I'll be okay.
But... Won't you be afraid when you see those berzerk eyes again?
If we lose to the Angels, we'll all die...
You're Commander Ikari's son, aren't you?
You don't trust your father's work?
Of course not! He's not much of a father...
Unidentified object analysis complete.
Compiling data.
Pattern blue. Angel confirmed.
As we thought. The 6th Angel.
Yes.
Prepare to sortie Unit 01.
Evangelion Unit 01, prepare to launch.
Moving to cage 1 runway.
The target has cleared Lake Ashinoko.
Evangelion Unit 01 is ready to launch.
Launch!
High energy reaction detected inside the target!
What?!
Impossible!
Get out of there!
Synchro rate dropped to 00%.
Raise protective armor!
Withdraw attack! Recover Eva Unit 01 immediately!
It's no good! The catapult is melting--it's unusable!
What about the A.T. field?
It's expanded to the limit, it's barely maintaining!
No! No, I can't!
Take me out--take me out, father!
We're breaking military protocal!
The pilot's life is our main priority! Force eject the plug!
You can't.
If the pilot is taken out, the A.T. field will completely collapse!
I know this is extremely hard to bear.
But...
Enough of this...
Force recover the fuselage! Ignite the blasting bolt!
The target has ceased fire.
-Recover Unit 01. Take first-aid to the cage!
-Put the rescue squad on stand-by!
Plug LCL coolant at it's highest level.
Pilot confirmed. Heartbeat is very weak!
Set plug suit life support to maximum. Begin heart massage!
Yes, sir!
Pulse confirmed!
Force expel the plug!
LCL drain in progress.
-Begin emergency LCL draining!
-Yes, sir!
Treat him, quickly!
The target is currently invading from above.
It is burrowing into the Geofront.
He's aiming to attack NERV Headquarters directly...
Well then, every department report in.
Judging from the previous battle...
...the target seems to automatically fire on any foreign object within it's space.
Then Eva won't be able to attack it directly...
How is it's A.T. field?
Active. To make matters worse...
...it has the ability to change phase space for external protection.
Neutralizing it will be very difficult.
Magi estimates that N2 Mines may pass through...
...it's A.T. field and cause unnecessary damage to NERV Headquarters.
Magi 2 in Matsushiro has made the same conclusion.
Presently, the Japanese Government and U.N. forces have proposed bombing NERV Headquarters.
It wouldn't work anyway.
If we lose here, it's all over.
Still, it's passed through the second armored layer.
It's already begun penetrating the third.
From today it will have to pass through 22 layers total.
It is expected to reach Headquarters tomorrow morning at 0 hours 06 minutes and 54 seconds.
That's 10 hours 14 minutes from now.
To make matters worse, Unit 00 is still not battle ready...
Unit 01 is also currently unmovable due to it's previous injury.
This isn't a very good situation.
We've covered everything, haven't we?
Ready to wave the white flag?
Not a bad idea... But before that, I think we should try a little something.
What about the emergency battle plan from the secret agency?
Well, you've drafted quite an insane plan, Captain Katsuragi.
Don't be rude.
It takes 9 hours to implement, and it's the plan with the highest probability of success.
Operation Yashima... It will require the electric power of the entire nation.
A battle plan revolving around experimental research...
...using a still incomplete positron beam cannon.
It's incomplete and hasn't been tuned for use by an Eva...
Well, it's convinced the U.N. forces and the JSDF.
We'll just have to borrow one.
A snake will gather it's friends...
As of midnight tonight, the entire country will suffer a large-scale blackout.
We ask for everyone's cooperation. Again...
Alright, here goes.
Yeah.
The enemy has penetrated through the 7th armored plate!
What is the status of the energy system?
Electric lines will pass through transformer substations directly to chamber 2.
Superconductivity Cable connecting to Mt. Futago is being constructed.
All voltage systems are set to direct there at 22 hours 50 minutes.
What about the sniping system?
No problems with assemply so far. We'll be ready somehow.
What is Unit 01's status?
It is currently being fitted with the sniping use G Mold Equipment.
It will be ready in another 2 hours.
Understood. Now for the pilots.
But, will he pilot it again?
What is the condition of Unit 01's pilot?
The dummy plug test went well.
We may have to make use of it if the pilot cannot fight.
A worst case scenario.
Now is not the time. We can still use Rei.
Rei in Unit 01? That's much too risky...
We must use any means to destroy the last 8 Angels.
And what then...
I hate piloting Eva.
Even if I do it, no one praises me.
If I fail, everyone will hate me. All that's left is a horrible death.
Why am I here...
If I could change things, I would leave this place.
And leave these thoughts.
If that's so, and you run away from bad things, you can continue to live?
Live?
Why am I alive?
I can't help but want to live...
Father, Misato-san, no one is there for me.
If I can't pilot Eva, I'm no longer needed.
Then I don't want to pilot Eva.
Then I don't want to be here.
But, when I do...
Another unknown ceiling.
When I pilot Eva, this is all I get.
Ayanami...
You've been here the whole time?
We will begin Operation Yashima at 00:00 hours.
Pilots Ikari and Ayanami are to report to Cage 2 at 1930 hours.
At 2000 hours Unit 01, and Unit 00 in a support role, will transfer.
At 2005 hours, we launch.
At 2030 we will arrive at Barricade 2 on Mt. Futago.
We will await further instructions there.
The mission begins at midnight.
Food.
I'm... not hungry.
We will leave in 90 minutes.
Then I'll... have to pilot it again.
Yes.
No, I can't. I don't want to have those scary thoughts again.
Too frightening... And I can't run away this time...
You're afraid of Eva?
Then stay and rest.
Rest?
I will pilot Unit 01.
Ayanami!
Good-bye.
The enemy is penetrating through 17th armored plate!
Target will reach Nerv Headquarters in 4 minutes 55 seconds.
That giant thing is the Positron Gun?
Even though it's still being constructed...
...there are no problems with the overall theory.
Zero Control forcibly linking G mold Equipment.
Well, we've done our part.
If only the pilots were so easy...
That's up to you, Misato.
Shinji-kun, you're behind schedule.
You made the decision to stay here, didn't you?
Do your part in this.
I'm afraid... To pilot Eva.
Misato-san and everyone else doesn't understand.
Always giving orders from safe underground...
Only I have to experience that fear...
You're all selfish!
Come with me.
15 years ago, the Second Impact tore the world in half.
If the Angels are ever to repeat the Second Impact...
...humanity would surely perish. Everyone.
I've heard all this before...
If an Angel ever reaches Level EEE of NERV Headquarters...
...an Automatic Self-Destruct would commence.
It is a necessary precaution against the Angels, and the Third Impact.
Everyone here shares that resolve.
This is...
It can't be...
...Eva?
No. While they began life under the same star...
...this is the second Angel: Lilith.
Lilith...?
Yes, the trigger of the Third Impact.
To protect Lilith, Eva must fight.
And you must do the same.
We have entrusted the future of humanity to Eva, and to you.
To do something so important... why me?
No particular reason. It's your fate.
You're not fighting alone, Shinji-kun.
Everyone is.
One more time. I'll pilot do it.
First, I'll explain the arrangements for this operation.
-Shinji-kun.
-Yes?
You will be gunning from Unit 01.
Yes.
Rei will defend you from Unit 00.
This mission will require precise, accurate operation.
For that reason, Unit 01 is more suited than the still unrepaired Unit 00.
Alright, Shinji-kun.
The positron beam is influenced by the Earth's rotation and local gravity....
...so it will not fire in a straight line.
Don't forget to adjust for that error.
You must strike the core in a single shot.
But we don't know where the core is!
It's alright. When the target is in attack form, something materializes within it.
We assume it is the core.
Regular shooting, and this sort of guided sniping are no different.
It's just like in the textbook. When the markers line up in the center, fire.
The computer takes care of the rest.
However, this operation will require a focused point of fire.
Unit 01 will not be able to move from it's firing position.
There's no retreating this time...
Yes.
Then if I miss, the enemy will return fire?
Don't think about that. Focus on destroying the target in one shot.
We're in a pretty big pinch, huh?
I... I will protect Unit 01.
Yes.
Understood.
It's time. You two go change.
-Yes.
I think...
...we might die this time.
No.
You won't die.
I will protect you.
I'm not much to protect.
There's a message from headquarters.
Ummm, this is Suzuhara.
Ikari, no, I should you Shinji...
Shinji, stay safe.
Ah, this is Aida.
Ikari, good luck.
Ayanami, why do you pilot Eva?
Because of my bond.
Your bond?
Yes. My bond.
With my father?
With everyone.
You're strong, Ayanami.
I don't have anything else.
It's time. Let's go.
Good-bye.
It is currently 00:00 hours. That is all.
It's time.
Shinji-kun, you've chosen to pilot Eva. That alone I'm grateful for.
Thank you.
Begin Operation Yashima.
Prepare Positron Rifle charge.
Initiate first connection.
Roger. Transfering power from water exchange unit.
All cooling systems at full power.
Initiate second connection.
-Starting all accelerators.
-Starting converger.
Transfering power from Mt. Gotemba sub-station. No problems detected.
-Initiate third connection.
-Roger. Beginning connection.
Transfering all energy to Mt. Futago substation.
-All connections running at maximum.
-All cooling systems running at full capacity.
No problems detected with third connection.
Understood. Transmit to barricades 4 and 5.
We'll be acting according to plan.
After observing it's reaction, take immediate action.
Defence systems 1 and 3 destroyed!
I see... nothing can pass within it's space. Next!
Barricade 2 has been hit!
All power is stored. No problems detected.
The final defence systems have been destroyed!
Pull back the sear!
Launcher Scope attached.
Adjust for the gravity field and revolution of the Earth by -0.0009.
Positron preparations complete.
Voltage up 0.2-0.1%.
Initiate fifth and final connenction!
All energy being transfered to Positron Gun.
Finalizing positron levels.
Momentum is steady through...
Even Ayanami doesn't care...
As skillfull as she is at piloting Eva, she still has no confidence.
She acts without even knowing why...
To protect humanity?
I can't feel passionate even if it's for something that important...
I wonder why...
13, 12, 11, 10...
9, 8, 7, 6...
5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
Fire!
Did we get it?!
-It changed?!
-It can't be! Terrible timing...
High energy reaction detected in the target!
All hands, brace for impact!
What's the status of the Energy System?
It's already begun to recharge.
The Positron Gun?
It's okay. The gun barrel is now cooling.
But we don't know if can manage another shot!
It doesn't matter--we'll do it anyway.
Shinji-kun, are you alright?!
Quickly, get Unit 01 back to firing position!
Shinji-kun?!
IF Unit 01's pilot is unable to take the shot, exchange places!
Unit 00 will take over.
Ikari!
If we're unable to use him, we have no other choice.
Please wait! He chose to pilot Eva without running away.
He chose this with his own will. I trust him!
Shinji, do us proud.
Ikari, good luck.
Believe in your son!
I believe in Unit 01's pilot!
I'll leave it to you then. Do as you please.
Thank you, sir!
Shinji-kun.
...Yes?
All of Japan's energy is with you.
All of our hopes, the future of humanity, and every living creature...
...has been entrusted to you. You can do it.
Yes!
Gun barrel in position!
Unit 01's G Mold Equipment has been discarded!
Final firing system switched to manual!
The enemy has reached the Headquarters!
Ready second shot!
Gun barrel fuse cooling complete!
Firing coordinates complete!
Calculations corrected! It's up to the pilot now!
Another high energy reaction detected in the target!
Watch out!
Shinji-kun!
Ayanami!
The shield won't be able to hold it!
Is it ready?!
20 more seconds!
Hurry... Hurry...
Hurry up!
We did it!
Ayanami!
Are you okay?!
Ayanami! Ayanami!
Don't say "I don't have anything else."
Don't say "good-bye" before a mission... it's too sad...
What? You're crying.
I'm sorry, I don't know what expression to have at times like these.
A smile is enough.
Yes, I know. That boy is awakening.
He has already entered the stage.
That's right. As it is written in The Dead Sea Scrolls.
The time to fulfill the contract is near.
They're only on the third one.
You never change, do you?
I look foward to meeting you, Ikari Shinji-kun.